Let's start by curating a dataset.
让我们首先来整理一个数据集
Neural networks by themselves can't really do anything.
神经网络本身不能做任何事
All a neural network really does is search for direct or
神经网络所做的唯一的事情就是
indirect correlation between two datasets.
搜索两个数据集之间直接或间接的相关性
So in order for neural network to train anything,
因此 为了让神经网络来做训练
we have to present it with two meaningful datasets.
我们需要给它提供 2 个有意义的数据集
The first dataset must represent what we know.
第一个数据集 必须代表我们已知的信息
And the second dataset must represent what we want to know,
第二个数据集 必须代表我们想要知道的信息
what we want the neural net to be able to tell us.
我们想要神经网络告诉我们什么答案
As the network trains, it's going to search for correlation between these
随着网络不断训练 它将不断寻找两组数据集之间的相关性
two data sets, so that eventually it can take one and learn to predict the other.
最终能够根据一组的输入 预测另一组的值
Let me show you what I mean with our example data set.
下面 我将用我们数据集的例子为大家说明
Right here we're going to kind of load into a list a set of IMDB movie reviews.
在这里 我们将载入一组 IMDB 的电影评论
So these are movie reviews that people uploaded to the site IMDB.
这些都是人们上传到 IMDB 网站的电影评论
These labels come with those reviews as
这些标签与评论一一对应
people have labeled them with one to five stars.
人们给电影从一星到五星打分
In this case we've bucketed them into just positive reviews being
在这里 我们简化成了正面评价：高于三星
higher than three stars and negative reviews being lower.
负面评价：低于三星
So, we have 25,000 reviews.
因此 我们这里有 25000 条评论
Here's an example of one of those reviews which is a negative review,
这里是一条负面评价的例子
I believe, yeah.
嗯 是的
And then, this one, we could see if it's a positive review and
然后 这一条 我们可以看到 它是一条正面评价
the label comes with a positive label.
标签也显示为 正面的标签
So, this is our dataset.
所以 这就是我们的数据集
Actually it's two data sets, right?
事实上是两个数据集 对吧？
So we have this data set which is what we know, and
因此 我们有了这组数据代表我们所知道的信息
what we will know in the future, right?
以及这一组 我们想要预测的数据 对吧？
And then this is what we want to know about the data set.
然后 这就是我们想要从数据集中了解的
So in this case we have two example data sets.
这个例子中 我们有两个数据集样本
We're going to try to train a neural network to take this as input and
我们要训练一个神经网络 将这些作为输入
be able to accurately predict this.
然后能准确地预测这个
So that when we see more human generated text in the future, in theory,
这样 未来我们看到更多人类生成的文本 从理论上讲
our neural net will be able to classify.
我们的神经网络将能够进行分类
The first thing we want to do when we encounter a dataset like is
我们拿到这样一个数据集 要做的第一件事
develop a predictive theory.
就是建立出一个预测理论
Now, a predictive theory is really about saying, okay, if I was the neural net,
预测理论实际上来说就是… 好 假设我是神经网络
and I was going to try to figure out how to look for
我试图找到一个方法
correlation in the data set, where would I look?
来发现数据集中的相关性 我会从哪里找？
Best thing that I like to do when developing predictive theory is just
我在构建预测理论时最喜欢做的就是
take a look at the dataset.
看看数据集
Try to figure out if I can solve this problem myself.
看看我自己是否能解决这个问题
And then sort of look inward and say,
然后就反躬自省
okay, what am I using maybe under the hood to kind of understand
我现在用的方法可能可以区分
whether this had a positive or negative sentiment.
这是否有正面或负面的情绪
So let's just read a few.
所以 让我们先来读几条电影评论吧
This movie was terrible, but it has some good effects.
“这部电影太糟糕了 但特效还可以”
Negative review, adrian pasdar is excellent in this film,
刚才这条是负面评论 “Adrian Pasdar 在影片中表现棒极了”
he makes a fascinating woman.
“他扮的女人很迷人”
Negative review, comment, this movie is impossible, is terrible,
负面评价 “这部电影怎么拍出来的！太烂了！”
very improbable, bad interpretation.
“完全不合逻辑 前后说不通”
Positive, excellent episode movie ala pulp fiction, days suicides,
正面评价 “非常棒的一部类似《低俗小说》的剧集式电影 7 天 7 次自杀” (注：原影评为 "7 days 7 suicides" 可能数字在抓取词库时被过滤了)
it doesn't get more, and then it continues on.
“它并没有…”  然后一条接着一条
So already I'm starting to kind of get a feel.
所以 读了之后 我已经有一种感觉
It seems to me pretty obvious these are really polarized examples.
对我来说 这些都是倾向性非常明显的评论
But what I'm going to be looking for is, okay, what in this
但我要寻找的是
is creating a correlation between my reviews data set and my labels data set.
究竟什么在评论数据集和标签数据集之间建立起了相关性
Well what is it in here?
相关性究竟来自什么？
This is a list of characters, right?
这是一个字符的列表 对吗？
So when I actually load it in, it says native format and it's just a list of,
所以 当我实际加载它 它本地的格式
I guess in this case 26 plus different characters.
只是 26+ 的不同字符组合
Is there correlation in its current state?
目前情况下是否存在相关性？
Well I don't really think that letter M or letter T has much predicted power.
我认为 字母 M 或字母 T 并不具备太强的预测能力
Right, so we have M in negative examples and we have M in positive examples.
我们在负面评价中有 M 在正面评价中也有 M
It doesn't really help us, so I don't think that would be a good source.
它并没有帮到我们 所以我不认为这是一个很好的来源
So the native state it's in right now is probably not very good.
所以 这些字符并不是一个很好的预测源
Now let's consider kind of the opposite
现在 我们换一种方式考虑
spectrum where we take the entire review as sort of what this dataset is.
我们将整条评论作为一个数据源
Well it is very predictive.
那么 它就有很强的预测性了
I mean, this review, every time we saw it, it was negative example.
我是指 我们每次看到这条评论时 都会判定它是负面评价的例子
Unfortunately, we only saw it once.
遗憾的是 我们只会看到它一次
And I think I can likely expect that most reviews we
我认为我们可以预期 将来看到的大多数评论
see in the future are going to be relatively original.
都会是相对原创的
We're going to see some people say this movie was terrible,
我们会看到有些人说 这部电影太糟糕了
or this movie was great, or really straightforward, things like that.
或者这部电影太棒了 或者真的很直接 类似的话
But most reviews have nuance.
但大多数评论有细微差别
They have a particular choice of words and
他们的遣词造句
sequence that's not just not really going to be duplicated very often.
都有个性 不是会经常重复出现的
So, training a neural net on the entire review might not work that well in
所以 如果针对整条评论来训练神经网络 实际效果不会太好
the real world because we just don't see it very often.
因为现实世界中 同样的评论并不经常出现
So, great correlation but kind of poor generalization.
所以 相关性很大 但泛化性差
What about kind of in between characters in the full review?
那么我们在字符和整条评论之间折中呢？
So I noticed that in NEGATIVE examples, we see words like terrible, and
我注意到 在负面评论中 经常出现一些词 比如 terrible (可怕的)、
improbable, and terrible, and terrible, and trash, and individual words that
improbable (不可能的)、terrible、terrible 和 trash (垃圾)
might have some correlation with these POSITIVE and NEGATIVE labels,
还有个别词 可能与这些正面和负面标签有一定相关性
in contrast to excellent, or fascinating, or excellent quality.
相反的词有 excellent (优秀的)、fascinating (迷人的) 或 excellent quality (优秀的品质)
So maybe it's just actually the counts of the different kinds of words
因此 可能只是不同词出现次数的计数
that are occurring in this, in these reviews.
它们在评论里出现了多少次
I think that's kind of a better theory.
我认为 这是一种更好的理论
Certainly better than characters and
肯定比字符更好
certainly better than the reviews as a whole.
也肯定比整条评论作为一个整体要好
But before we just kind of run off creating a neural net,
但在我们草草建立一个神经网络前
I find that it's best to sort of do a quick validate, right?
我认为我们最好做一个快速的验证 对吧？
So, this is something that we think is true with the theory that we have.
这是我们认为正确的理论
But before we actually go and
在我们正式开始之前
do everything, we should see if what we have is naively predictable, right?
我们要看一下 我们的预测是否真的奏效 对吧？
Now what I typically do here is I just, I count them.
这里 我通常做的只是 数一数次数
Or I formulate a count based heuristic to try to see, okay, does
或者说 我设定了基于计数的启发式尝试 来看看
this phenomenon seem to happen more for this label than it does for this label?
这一现象在这种标签上的出现频率是否要高于那一种标签？
Right, is it a good [INAUDIBLE].
这是一个很好的标签分类器
So the first project that I would like for you to tackle and
所以 我要大家做第一个项目
then I will show you how I tackle it, is to just think about how you would take
然后我会告诉大家 我是怎么解决的 第一个项目就是想一想
this data set and validate our theory that words are predictive of labels.
你会如何处理数据集 然后验证我们的理论是可以给出正确的预测
So go ahead and take a few minutes and take a crack at it and see if you can
好了 去做吧 花几分钟来解决它 看看能否
kind of just come up with a way of showing either is or is not predictive.
找到一种方法 来显示 “具有” 或 “不具有” 预测性